supreme court has made some stern
observations as the hearing into the
telecom agr matter resumes
it says it will direct the government to
cancel spectrum allotted to telecom
companies if they're unwilling to pay
the government
what they owe the supreme court has also
observed that selling of spectrum
allows produce to be wiped out and this
is not permissible
asks why the dot did not raise any
demands against airtel produce that
accrued on spectrum bought from videocon
delhi high court issues notices to the
center and the reserve bank on a plea
seeking action against google pay the
plea
alleges that google pay has violated rbi
norms
on data localization storage and sharing
the chan zuckerberg initiative a
non-profit headed by facebook
ceo mark zuckerberg and his wife
priscilla chan is in advanced talks to
invest in indian learning startup
eruditis the startup offers management
programs and short courses remotely
and has tie-ups with foreign
universities including colombia mit and
harvard business school
that's a money control exclusive
icici lombard is all set to acquire and
merge bharti axa general insurance into
itself in an all-share deal worth 4
600 crores the deal would make icici
lombard the third largest non-life
insurer in india with a market share of
nearly 8.7 percent
the oem distribution uh there uh
obviously we are pretty strong in that
channel but again if you
uh slice and dice that number and you
look at
certain oems they're pretty strong
relative to their size in certain oems
and
there we believe uh while we may be
strong in some of them but
uh you know the the complementarity in
terms of the specific dealerships that
they're
working in versus where we are working
in there could be some amount of
benefit that we will get and if you look
at our aggregate market share in motor
we would increase from roughly over 10
percent to about 12 percent on a pro
forma basis
all right and staying with more news a
cabinet committee of secretaries will
meet to discuss the road forward on
concord and bpl
bpc at strategic stake sales sources say
cnbc tv 18
that railways will formalize the land
licensing fee for concourse take sales
soon we also learn the government is
keen to conclude the bpcl steak sale in
the current fiscal
well here's a money control exclusive
kalyan jewelers has filed its draft red
herring prospectus with the market
regulator for an ipo worth 1750 crores
the kerala blaze jewelry retailers
backed by
p investor warburg pinkis ashbin joined
us now with more ashwin
so uh kalyan jules filing for an ipo
right so when was the last time that you
heard of a jewelry ipo hitting the
domestic capital markets
that was nearly eight years back 2012
december pc dwellers
now what we're picking up from our
sources is that kerala based
jewelry retail firm kalyan dwellers
which is backed by
private equity giant warburg pinkus has
filed a drhp today with market regulator
sebi
for an ipo to raise around 1750 crore
rupees
now this ipo is going to be split into
two components there's a fresh issue
component
and that's thousand crore rupees and you
have the promoters
as well as robert pincus that are going
to dilute stake
worth 250 crore rupees and 500 crore
rupees
respectively what's the rationale for
the ipo well the ipo
is being done to a facilitate a partial
exit for the pe investor that's bobot
pincus
also for working capital to help in
expansion of stores and to facilitate
debt reduction
to a certain extent access capital ics
securities
city and sbi capital are the investment
banks
working on this proposed ipo now the
drhp filing mind you has come in a very
interesting time because
the entire sector is in fact slowly
recovering from the absolute pounding
that it received
due to uh kovid due to the peak of covet
19 wherein footfalls were hit
when sales were hit and of course the
sector is hoping for a complete
revival during the festive season and
during the wedding season but uh gold
prices also
have been pretty volatile and choppy uh
from the recent
highs or the recent record highs that
they touched if you look at the listed
pairs when the listed pairs their stocks
have rallied pretty sharply
in the last three months the likes of
titan the likes of weber global the
likes of renaissance global
those stocks have seen an upward
trajectory in the last three months
robert pinkers has about a 30 stake in
kalyan jewelers if you look at kalyan's
it has more than 135 outlets or
showrooms in
19 states and about two union
territories it is present overseas as
well in five countries
especially the middle east region and it
also has an online brand
called candia now the big question is
will this lead
to other dwellers like uh joya lucas or
malabar dwellers to also eye the ipo
route well
we'll have to wait and see